<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mercury | Yujuan Wang</title><link>http://localhost:1313/tag/mercury/</link><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tag/mercury/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Mercury</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu5690424224879592292.png</url><title>Mercury</title><link>http://localhost:1313/tag/mercury/</link></image><item><title>Potential Decoupling of CO2 and Hg Uptake Process by Global Vegetation in the 21st Century</title><link>http://localhost:1313/publication/yuan-potential-2024/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/yuan-potential-2024/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Climate-Driven Changes of Global Marine Mercury Cycles in 2100</title><link>http://localhost:1313/publication/wang-climate-driven-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/wang-climate-driven-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>How will future climate change impact marine mercury cycling?</title><link>http://localhost:1313/project/hg-climate-change/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/project/hg-climate-change/</guid><description>&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="flex justify-center ">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Summary" srcset="
/project/hg-climate-change/banner_hu1937038408508529567.webp 400w,
/project/hg-climate-change/banner_hu15603678290950494332.webp 760w,
/project/hg-climate-change/banner_hu9772155092117699647.webp 1200w"
src="http://localhost:1313/project/hg-climate-change/banner_hu1937038408508529567.webp"
width="612"
height="300"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mercury (Hg) is a persistent global pollutant, and its transformation in the ocean plays a critical role in its biogeochemical cycle. Methylmercury (CH3Hg), a potent neurotoxin formed by marine microbes, accumulates through the marine food web, ultimately affecting human health through seafood consumption. Climate change, driven by human activities, has caused significant alterations in ocean conditions—such as rising temperatures, acidification, and biodiversity loss—that influence mercury cycling and its uptake by marine organisms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="flex justify-center ">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Minamata Convention" srcset="
/project/hg-climate-change/f3_hu14181772201823671215.webp 400w,
/project/hg-climate-change/f3_hu7336428582799659240.webp 760w,
/project/hg-climate-change/f3_hu12346642124717003567.webp 1200w"
src="http://localhost:1313/project/hg-climate-change/f3_hu14181772201823671215.webp"
width="661"
height="443"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One concern raised by climate-induced changes in the oceans is the potential increase of neurotoxic methylmercury in seafood. In our study, we examined how global climate change, under a business-as-usual emission scenario, affects the global ocean mercury cycle by integrating data from 3D marine biogeochemical, ecosystem, and Earth system models. We identified several key pathways through which climate change alters marine mercury dynamics. These include reduced air-sea exchange due to weaker winds, decreased particulate organic carbon export affecting mercury deposition, and increased photodemethylation of methylmercury due to higher shortwave radiation. Collectively, these changes suggest a complex interaction between physical, chemical, and biological factors that influence mercury levels in the oceans. &lt;em>This following video provides a brief illustration of the impact pathways identified in our research.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls >
&lt;source src="http://localhost:1313/project/hg-climate-change/PNAS-Hg-summary.mp4" type="video/mp4">
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>Our research offers a broad perspective on this issue, highlighting the intricate interplay of factors, including climate dynamics and ocean ecology. Our findings reveal that while some aspects of climate change exacerbate mercury release, others, such as enhanced photodegradation of methylmercury, may reduce its concentration in seawater and marine life. This could buy us time to mitigate the release of mercury into the environment. Our results underscore the necessity of a holistic approach to studying the impact of climate change, considering both its potential benefits and detriments. This insight is valuable for guiding future policymaking, aligning it with multiple planetary boundaries, and fostering sustainable practices in a changing world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="flex justify-center ">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Climate change" srcset="
/project/hg-climate-change/f2_hu14018838963856213193.webp 400w,
/project/hg-climate-change/f2_hu10413155119242990557.webp 760w,
/project/hg-climate-change/f2_hu5999016353693452382.webp 1200w"
src="http://localhost:1313/project/hg-climate-change/f2_hu14018838963856213193.webp"
width="727"
height="446"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="flex justify-center ">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Summary" srcset="
/project/hg-climate-change/featured_hu16490158821945323521.webp 400w,
/project/hg-climate-change/featured_hu10425428705667988523.webp 760w,
/project/hg-climate-change/featured_hu3324733506018108328.webp 1200w"
src="http://localhost:1313/project/hg-climate-change/featured_hu16490158821945323521.webp"
width="760"
height="285"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>